What about the Q&A session?
Where should we put it in the presentation?
It’s scary just to think about it
I don’t know how to handle questions
Don’t worry
If you follow some simple guidelines
you should have no problem at all
First, you should let your audience know
when they can ask questions
You could even give the audience
some instructions for asking questions
Sometimes the audience is told to raise questions
whenever they have one
Yes, I’ve heard some speaker say
“Feel free to interrupt me
if there are any questions.”
But I prefer to leave the Q&A session until the end
Then you could say, “I am happy to
answer any questions after the presentation”
or “I’ll leave ten minutes at the end for questions.”
You can also invite your audience
to bring up questions
“Are there any questions for me?”
or “I am glad to answer any questions now.”
Sometimes I’m not sure
if they’re satisfied with my answers.
How should I check again?
It wouldn’t hurt to double check by saying
"Does this answer your question?"
or "Do you follow what I am saying?"
What if I don’t understand what they’re asking?
How can I ask them to clarify?
You could say “I’m sorry
but I don’t quite understand your question
Could you rephrase it?”
I might not know the answer to their questions
How could I explain that?
You can honestly let them know that
I am afraid I don’t have the answer at the moment
I’ll check on it and get back to you later
or Good question. What do the rest of you think?
And remember to thank your audience
for asking questions
That’s a good question. Thank you for bringing it up
or “I am glad you asked that question
Usually the question session is followed by the closing
How do I signal to the audience
that I won’t be able to take any more questions?
Use a sentence like
Are there any other questions at this point?
or I think I have time for one last question
or If there are no more questions, I’ll leave it here
This is a hint to the audience
that the Q&A session is about to end
Ok, if you don’t have any other questions
it’s time for us to go
Ok, I got the hint
Thanks for the tips. Talk to you later